

# **Curriculum Vitae for Jonathan Feinberg**

### Personal information

Address: Pilestredet park 15 E-mail: jonathan@xal.no

0176 Oslo Phone: +47 93 21 44 74

Born: 28.04.1984

# **Summary**

I am a specialist in probability theory, statistics and machine learning with heavy focus on numerical programming and practical applications. I am highly analytical in my thinking and can quickly break down open ended complex problems into manageable components. At the same time I am also an experienced programmer, with expert level knowledge in the Python programming language.

### **Technical skills**

Frameworks Armadillo, GIS, Keras/Tensorflow, Matplotlib, NumPy/SciPy, Pandas,

PyMC, Scikit-Learn, Statsmodels, XGBoost

Languages Bash, C, C++, LaTFX, MATLAB, Python, R, RST/Markdown, Vim-

script, Regular Expression

Tools Continuous Integration, Version Control Systems, Documentation Ge-

neration

#### Education

2015 PhD in Mathematics from the Department of Mathematics, University

of Oslo.

Thesis written at Simula Research Laboratory: "Some Improvements and Applications and Non-intrusive Polynomial Chaos Expansions"

Supervised by Professor Hans Petter Langtangen.

2009 Master's degree in Modelling and Data Analysis, Department of

Mathematics, University of Oslo.

Thesis written at Norwegian Geotechinical Institute: "Threshold De-

finition of Early Warning Systems to Natural Hazards"

Supervisor by Professor Bent Natvig.

2007 Bachelor's degree in Mathematics, Informatics and Technology, Uni-

versity of Oslo

# **Professional experience**

2016 -	Consultant at Expert Analytics
2016 -	Guest lecturer at the Department of Informatics, University of Oslo
2014 - 2015	Teaching Position at the Department of Informatics, University of Oslo
2014 - 2015	Private tutor at high school and undergraduate level at House of Math
2014 - 2015	Scientific Programmer for Simula Research Laboratory
2013 - 2014	Consultant at Kalkulo AS
2011 - 2014	Ph.D. student at Simula Research Laboratory
2009 - 2010	Research Assistant at Texas A&M University
2009 - 2009	Science Teacher at Smerud Medical Research
2008	Assistant Teacher at Department of Mathematics, University of Oslo
2007 - 2008	Student Ambassador at Public Relations and Events Office, University
	of Oslo
2007	Data Analyst at If P&C Insurance

# Languages

English Fluent

Norwegian Mother tongue

### Personal skills

Communication I am able to convey research and condensed knowledge into a presen-

table and explainable form. Extensive experience as university lecturer

and teacher.

Planning I am a "Problem solver", able to see strengths and weaknesses of

proposed progress plans, grounded in fact-based thought.

Technology I have a high enthusiasm for learning and mastering new skills within

science, technology and programming.

### Some interests and hobbies

Personal Traveling, Gin tasting

Tech Bayesian Statistics/Probabilistic Modelling, Open Source Software,

Machine Learning, Global Optimization Algorithms, Python program-

ming